A New Evil Awakens.
The Mummy: Tomb of the Dragon Emperor is a adventure,
action, fantasy film directed by Rob Cohen.
Archaeologist Rick O'Connell travels to China, pitting him against an emperor from the
2,000-year-old Han dynasty who's returned from the dead to pursue a quest for world domination.
This time, O'Connell enlists the help of his wife and son to quash the
so-called 'Dragon Emperor' and his abuse of supernatural power.
Rick O'Connell, played by Brendan Fraser.
Evelyn O'Connell, played by Maria Bello.
Jonathan Carnahan, played by John Hannah.
Alex O'Connell, played by Luke Ford.
Lin, played by Isabella Leong Lok-Sze.
Han, played by Jet Li.
The Mummy: Tomb of the Dragon Emperor is a 2008 American action adventure fantasy film directed by Rob Cohen, written by Alfred Gough and
Miles Millar, and produced by Stephen Sommers (director of the first two films), Bob Ducsay, Sean Daniel, and James Jacks.
The film is set in China rather than Egypt and
focuses on the Terracotta Army's origins.
It is the third installment in The Mummy series.
It stars Brendan Fraser, Jet Li, Maria Bello (replacing Rachel Weisz, who played Evelyn in
the first two films), John Hannah, Luke Ford, Anthony Wong, and Michelle Yeoh.
The Mummy: Tomb of the Dragon Emperor premiered in Moscow on July 24, 2008,
and was released in the United States on August 1, 2008.
The film was a commercial success, grossing $405.8 million worldwide, though it was the
lowest-grossing film in the trilogy and received generally negative reviews from critics.
Universal Pictures rebooted the Mummy franchise with a 2017 reboot film, in an
attempt to start a cinematic universe under the name Dark Universe.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of china, sword, pyramid, mummy, yeti.